♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix it ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Dmitri] You won't get
your father back if you kill Red.
[Audrey screams, in English] Dad! Dad!
[Martina, in English] Oh my God.
[Martina, in English] You know,
this is all Atoy's fault,
but this is also on you!
This wouldn't have happened if Red
hadn't done something to Atoy's father!
For once, side with your own family!
Tatoy, what happened to your hand?
[Audrey] Did Atoy
really mean to shoot you?
[in English] Yes, he did.
He's not that kind of person, Dad.
[Karla] He even forbade Gavin
from being friends with me.
- [Emerson] Gavin Regalia, Red's son?
- [Karla] Yes.
Karla, Gavin's father was the one
who hit-and-run Sir Delfin.
What?
How can I tell our child
that you almost killed her grandfather?!
Will we be safe with you?!
[Gavin, in English] He asked me
where my Dad was last night.
Turns out he already had--
had something bad planned for Dad.
I just really wanted to have
a happy and complete family.
I thought it would happen
when Audrey and Janine were given to me.
We're still here, Tatoy.
[Ibyang] We may not be blood-related, but…
we're still your family.
We're not a drawing that can be erased.
Brother, sorry if I haven't
been around lately.
[Karla] Sorry if I've been stubborn.
‪PREVIOUSLY
[music fades]
[softly] Thank you.
[utensils clattering]
Karla, thank you for what you did earlier.
Atoy appreciated that you were there.
Especially now that
he's going through something.
Mom, I did not apologize to Brother Atoy
because I was stubborn.
I apologized because he thinks
we're honest with him, but…
we're not.
He doesn't need to know that.
Karla, I hope
you trust me.
I hope you'll tell me everything too.
Mom, what else should I say to you?
The man who brought you home,
is he your boyfriend now?
Gavin?
Oh, no.
Ah, he looks kind and trustworthy.
Invite him to dinner here sometime,
I'll cook for him,
as a thank you for bringing you home.
Mom, I don't know
if we'll still be friends.
Hmm? Why not?
Mom, his father killed my father,
Sir Delfin.
He's Red Regalia's son.
That's why I don't know
if we'll still be friends,
even if I want to.
[suspicious music playing]
[music fades]
[Gavin] Karla.
Gavin.
How are you?
Wait, let me just get your jacket.
Karla, wait.
Did you hurt Cathy?
We fought, but she started it.
You really take after
your Brother Atoy, huh?
You're hot-headed too.
Why is Brother Atoy involved?
Don't tell me you don't know what he did?
He shot my grandfather.
He beat up my father!
He's lucky my grandfather
won't press charges
because he's thinking of Janine!
Why?
Your father deserved it!
He killed Sir Delfin,
Brother Atoy's and my father!
What evidence does your brother have
to accuse him, huh?
Did he see my dad himself?
Did he see him commit the hit-and-run?!
Or maybe he's just looking for trouble!
You don't know Brother Atoy!
He's not like your father!
Your brother isn't a saint!
Okay? He's just like your father!
They're both pretenders!
What you're saying is foul!
Don't drag my father into this. He's dead!
And he was killed by your criminal father!
I wish I hadn't told you my problems,
if you'd just use them against me!
[tense music playing]
Leave now!
Get out! Out!
Leave!
[sobbing]
[suave theme music playing]
But, miss, do you think
Atoy and Audrey broke up?
That's the vibe I got last night.
I just feel sad for Atoy
because neither of them
wants this situation.
Maybe they're really not meant to be.
It's hard when your partner's family
are all hoodlums.
Then blood gets spilled in their family.
That's a big no-no.
[sighs] I just want Atoy
to have his own family.
You know, miss, sometimes Atoy and I
seem cursed in things like this.
- Single?
- [quirky sting]
- It's hard to be handsome.
That's our "handsome problems".
Sometimes the world just isn't fair.
[Ame] Oh.
It's hot outside, but it's windy here.
Signal number three!
Doesn't seem like it.
Ame, weren't you with Atoy
when you took Ibyang to school?
Has he arrived at the tailoring shop?
Oh, he hasn't.
The thing is, Miss Cita,
Atoy wanted to see Janine,
but he found out Janine
was already pulled out from school.
It looks like Audrey is avoiding
a meeting between father and daughter.
So, where is Atoy now?
Oh, no.
[pensive music playing]
I think I know.
I think I know where Atoy is.
Sir, they're not here,
so please don't cause a scene.
- [Emerson] Boss, wait.
- [indistinct]
- My companion. Hold on.
She's not at her house,
and I know this is where she'd come.
So, call your master, bring Audrey out.
- [Emerson] Wait, wait, wait.
- [Atoy] Audrey!
Wait, wait, brother. Atoy, Atoy!
Hold on. Ah. Calm down first.
Sir, I'll handle this.
- I'll handle him.
- Call her!
- [Emerson] Sorry, yes.
- Call her.
- Okay. I'll handle it.
- No, call her. Surely she's there!
'Toy, 'Toy, calm down first.
Leave Audrey alone for now.
Maybe she just needs space.
Of course, you still want her, but…
maybe she's just thinking
about her next move.
You shouldn't have stormed here.
Aren't you nervous
about what you're doing?
I'm not doing anything.
I just want to talk. That's all.
- Hey, Gavin!
- [in English] Bro Atoy, you should leave.
Gavin, talk to your Aunt Audrey.
Tell her, if she doesn't
want to talk to me,
she shouldn't involve Janine.
I've been calling her. She won't answer.
Tell her to talk to me properly.
[music fades]
Why? What's so funny?
You have the nerve
to order me around, huh?
[in English] After what you did
to my family?
I thought you were kind!
I'm not kind,
especially to murderers like your father.
You have no evidence!
I know my father's reputation!
[in English] But he doesn't deserve
what you did to him,
and especially to my grandfather!
You know, I pity you.
I know you're a good kid.
You're just surrounded by liars.
[pensive music playing]
You're the pitiful one!
There are more liars around you!
Why don't you ask Karla?!
What?
Who?
- [Gavin] No one.
- Karla?!
- No-- No one.
- [Atoy] What do you mean, no one?
What about Karla? Huh, Gavin?
[tense music playing]
- Uh--
- What about Karla?!
[music swells, fades]
Is Atoy there?
Just ignore him.
He'll leave soon.
[pensive music playing]
Mommy, are you okay?
Janine, child.
Is it okay with you
not to be with your daddy for now?
I was thinking,
once we get clearance
from your grandfather's doctor…
I want us
to go to the States.
We're going to America?
I want that, Mommy. I want to see snow!
Is it okay with you not to see
your daddy anymore?
It's okay. He's bad anyway.
He hurt Grandpa.
[melancholic music playing]
- What were you saying about Karla?! Gavin!
- [dramatic sting]
- [Emerson] Enough, enough, enough.
- [Gavin] Nothing, nothing.
No, you were saying something!
- [Emerson] Enough, 'Toy.
- What is it?!
- Gavin, enough, enough.
- Gavin, what about Karla--
Sir, just relax. [groaning]
Huh? Gavin!
Gavin!
- Gavin!
- [Emerson mutters]
‪-[muttering]
‪-[groaning]
No. It's fine now. It's fine.
It's fine, sir. Okay, it's fine.
It's okay. We'll handle it.
I'll take care of it.
[tense music playing]
'Toy, let's go. Come on.
Let's go.
[in English] So, Dad, you're just gonna
let Atoy get away with everything?
He shot you!
Our men died and were hurt.
[in English] He's entitled
to that rage, Martina.
He didn't mean to shoot me.
That damned husband of yours pulled me,
that's why I got shot!
Dad, you don't need to say that.
[in English] You're being unfair to Red.
It's all his fault anyway.
From that hit-and-run
to what happened to me.
[in English] He's stupid and a coward!
[suspicious music playing]
I want to file a case,
but then there'll be an investigation,
and the details
of what he did will come out.
Dad, did Audrey ask you?
[in English] It was my decision.
I just made it seem to Audrey
that Atoy intentionally shot me,
so she'd get angry at him
and leave that man.
Isn't that what you wanted?
If Red was the only reason,
Audrey wouldn't leave Atoy.
[music fades]
Nurse, what room
is Red Regalia confined in?
I'll get back to you, sir.
Wait a moment. Excuse me.
[phone ringing]
[grunts]
Roger, what's the news?
I found the nun Boss Red was looking for.
She's with her niece.
[Mongki on the phone] I'll let you know.
You can't talk to Boss Red yet.
Just don't take your eyes off them.
Understand?
Copy.
Brother, will it take long?
- [man] Ah, Ma'am, here it is.
- [Faye] Oh. Oh, here. Thank you!
Auntie Norma, our order is here.
[Norma] Hmm! Thank you.
Auntie, Doc's secretary texted me.
Looks like Doc will be late,
so we can arrive around 6 p.m. instead.
[mutters]
[stammers] Did-- Did you get
Ame's number?
Ah, not yet.
Her coworker hasn't texted me.
But she told me yesterday
she'd ask their coworkers.
Who else are you looking for, besides Ame?
[mutters]
- [stammers] It's--
- [niece] It's…
A-- A…
to-- toy.
Sorry.
I pretended to be a nun.
This was the only way I could talk to you.
[in English] Sister…
[in English] Ivy Santos, eight years old.
We call her Ibyang.
She's a good kid, but…
a bit mischievous and cheeky.
But still kind.
I'm sending her to school.
Atoy?!
Ah. Do you know Atoy's full name?
Maybe I can find him on the Internet.
[stammers] Or-- even A--Ame.
Be-- because…
she's the one…
who will lead…
us-- to A-- Atoy
and Ib--yang.
[music fades]
Emerson, watch over Atoy, okay?
And don't go back to the Regalia house.
Okay. Be careful.
[in English] Bye.
How's Atoy?
[sighs]
Audrey didn't face Atoy.
He almost fought with Red's son, Gavin.
[sighs] Unbelievable.
Atoy really needs a vacation.
You and Ibyang should go with him, okay?
Yes. I'm game for that.
Want a snack?
- Sure.
- I'll get some.
[grunts softly]
I'm really game for that.
Especially now that things are unclear
between Audrey and Atoy.
[phone ringing]
Hello? Who is this?
Ms. Ame?
I got your number from Ms. Grace,
your former coworker at Home of Tomorrow.
I'm Sister Norma's niece.
We're here in Manila!
Sister Norma is alive?
Yes. She just arrived last week.
She wants to talk to you
about Ibyang's parents.
Can we meet later?
Ah, yes-- Okay. Where can we meet you?
[tense music playing]
Why didn't he have him jailed?
What the hell? Was he hypnotized by Atoy?
[in English] Dad has his reason.
And don't contradict him.
You're already being blamed
for everything.
Of course.
[scoffs] I'm always at fault.
He'd probably be happier if I were dead.
[in English] Hon,
he was protecting you from Atoy.
It's better he's not in jail.
It's easier for me to get revenge outside.
Oh, and then?
If you do that, Dad will be even angrier.
[in English] Even if Dad
doesn't like Atoy,
he's tied to Audrey.
You know how strong
Audrey's influence is on Dad.
That's another problem.
I need to think of a way
to get back at him.
That bastard always gets lucky.
[anxious music playing]
Don't think about that now, okay?
The day will come
when you'll have Atoy by the neck.
[phone ringing]
Now you're calling me.
Tsk! Whatever.
If it's two, it's straight--
- straight through.
- Oop, oop, oop.
Oh, there. Karla!
Karla, look.
Help me, Karla!
- It's fine, it's fine…
- Emerson!
- [Emerson] Sit here. Stay here.
- [Atoy groans]
- [Cita] What the hell?!
- [groans]
- Didn't I say, stay with him?
- [Emerson chuckles]
Why did you bring him home drunk?!
I did stay with him!
I stayed to drink with him!
He invited me, of course.
Miss, come on.
How could I not go with him?
Better than him hanging out again
outside Audrey's house.
- Yes.
- [Cita mutters]
[Cita] Stay with him.
I'll get a towel.
[Emerson giggles]
[groans]
- [Emerson] Wa-Wait, I'll go to the CR.
- Oh my!
- [Emerson] CR. Where's the CR?
- Go ahead.
[Emerson coughing]
Drinking doesn't suit you. What's this?
Pull yourself together!
- [pensive music playing]
- [inhales]
[Atoy grunts]
[Atoy] Hey, Karla.
‪[inhales]
‪[exhales]
Gavin told me something.
He said you're a liar.
[sinister music playing]
Are you hiding something from me?
Brother, I don't know about that.
Nothing.
[music fades]
[melancholic music playing]
Karla, I've known you
since you were a child.
I know when you're lying.
I see it in your eyes.
There.
I feel it in your pulse.
So?
Do you have something to tell me?
- [in English] Brother, I'm sorry.
- Hmm?
Is there something I should know?
Or something you need to admit…
Why would he call you a liar?
- Brother, I don't know how!
- Huh?
[Atoy] Huh? How?
I just hope you won't be angry with us.
Angry?
[Karla] I hope you won't be angry with us.
Karla!
Why would I be angry with you?
Let your Brother Atoy rest.
- Emerson!
- Godmother, what is she saying?
Emerson! Take Atoy upstairs
so he can lie down properly. Go on!
- [Atoy] Godmother, Karla!
- [Cita] Take him upstairs.
[Emerson] Yes.
[Atoy] W-Why--
Wow.
That's a lot.
[Emerson humming]
[sighs]
- [music fades]
- [Emerson chuckles]
[Emerson] So many.
- [suspicious music playing]
- [Emerson belches]
[Cita] Karla, what was that?
Are you going to tell Atoy the truth?
Didn't I warn you?
Mom, it seems Brother Atoy
already knows something.
It should come from us, Mom.
No, Karla.
We won't add more
to what he's going through.
How do you know he knows?
Did you tell anyone else?
No, Mom.
He just brought it up now.
How would he have an idea
if no one told him?
[tense music playing]
So, your real father
is Brother Atoy's father?
[in English] That makes him
your half-brother.
[pensive music playing]
[barker] Baclara, Baclaran, Baclaran!
Baclaran! Baclaran!
[barker] Baclaran, Baclaran, Baclaran!
[Atoy] Ma, are you with Dad too?
[Julie on the phone] No.
He'll be home later.
He said he's meeting a client outside.
Ah, is that so?
[pensive music playing]
[sighs]
O-Okay, Ma.
I'll-- I'll head home too.
[suspicious music playing]
[Emerson] Mmm?
[Emerson] Hey, 'Toy.
Don't touch Miss Cita's bag.
Go upstairs to your room.
Go on. I have somewhere to go too.
Hmm, I'll just go with you, Sir Delfin.
You're good at buying, huh?
[young Karla] Dad!
My hair!
[Delfin] Come on, hurry.
[epic music playing]
Godmother.
I'm sorry, Karla.
I know you're struggling,
but he shouldn't know the truth.
[melodramatic music playing]
Mom, isn't it better
if he learns the truth from us?
Rather than figuring it out himself?
Godmother.
Is this yours?
Yes, Atoy.
[Cita titters]
Atoy, why?
I'll never forget this scarf.
[suspicious music playing]
Because I saw this.
[music fades]
I saw this on
my father's mistress.
[heavy music playing]
[scoffs]
Why, of all men, does it have to be
my father, Godmother?
[sobs]
[music swells]
I'll grow old single.
I'm here, Master.
Even if my parents take me,
I'll still come to you.
All this time, Audrey's real child
has been right around us.
But we need to plan this.
UP NEXT
We need to get ahead of Atoy.
It's risky. They're in the same house.
[Red] He must not know
that Ibyang is his child.
[Mongki] Don't do anything bad.
- Brother.
- Or you'll go straight to the morgue.
[in English] Hello, Sister Norma.
Remember me?
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix this ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias